# **Ellie Chen**

ellie.tt.chen@gmail.com · 0475-255-677

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliettchen/

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Before switching career to web development, I have had more than 3-years professional experience in the migration industry, specialising in accounting skills assessment and individual migration. During my time with Coder Academy, I was able to plan, design and implement several applications from scratch to final products. As a developer, I look forward to combining my multi-disciplined domain knowledge and strong programming skills to support both businesses and clients to achieve the desired outcomes.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

# **Aussie Beauty Market**

https://aussie-beauty-market.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Aussie-Beauty-Market

- Two-sided marketplace website on Ruby on Rails for trading second-hand makeup in Australia.
- E-commerce application, restful API, user authentication & authorisation, simple & advanced search capabilities, payment processing function, Q&A section and responsive web design.

#### **Portfolio Website**

https://elliechen.netlify.com/

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Portfolio-Site Ellie-Chen

- Portfolio website to showcase my web development skills and to demonstrate my professional experiences, transferable skills, personal projects, interests and personality.
- Different CSS/JavaScript effects on every webpage, fixed navigation bar and social icons bar, accessibility, sub-resource integrity and responsive web design.

#### **Oriental Zodiac Patronus**

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Oriental-Zodiac-Patronus

- Terminal application on Ruby to promote the Chinese horoscope (Chinese zodiac animals) to general public. Also serves as a fun and interactive educational game with family and friends.
- Chinese Zodiac Animal Test (find out your Chinese zodiac animal), Animal Compatibility Test (find out your perfect and worst matched zodiac animals) and Tai Sui Test (luck prediction in 2020).

#### **COMPETENCIES**

- **Programming Languages:** Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SASS.
- **Dependencies**: Git, GitHub, AWS (S3 & IAM), deployment platforms (Heroku, Netlify), payment processing (Stripe), wireframe (Balsamiq) and sub-resource Integrity hash (sha-512).
- Soft skills:

Sound written and verbal communication skills with a strong customer focus.

Strong time and task management skills in a proven problem-solving approach.

High resilience, excellent concentration and a positive can-do attitude at work.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## **Migration Coordinator/Migration Executive**

Aug 2016 - Aug 2019

Chartered Accountants Australia & New Zealand (Sydney, Australia)

- Conducting migration assessment with high attention to details and identifying training needs.
- Interpreting the latest legislation changes and advising on difficult migration assessment issues.
- Proven time-management skills in handling high volumes of applications, prioritising tasks, meeting deadlines, and working autonomously and cooperatively in a high-performing professional team.

## **Assistant Migration Consultant**

Sep 2014 – Jul 2016

Ausky Visa Solutions (Sydney, Australia)

- Efficiently managing a client's visa application from the initial engagement, eligibility assessment, follow-up correspondence, application lodgment to final decision, with a 95% visa approval rate.
- Effectively facilitating the communication between the mandarin-speaking clients and other English-speaking parties, including Immigration case officers and skills assessing authorities.

# **Localisation Project Manager and Translator**

Jul 2010 - Jun 2011

Weasto Translation Company (Taipei, Taiwan)

- Intelligently organising translation projects, conducting human resource deployment of inhouse/freelance translators and editors, and liaising with international clients and local vendors.
- Effectively managing a one-million-words Expedia.com project and achieving scheduled goals.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Diploma in Information Technology/Full-time Fast-track Bootcamp

Coder Academy (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 (expected)

**Graduate Certificate in Australian Migration Law and Practice** (High Distinction Average)

The Australian National University (Canberra, Australia)

May 2017 - Nov 2017

**Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting** (High Distinction Average)

Victoria University (Sydney, Australia)

Jul 2015 - Apr 2016

**Postgraduate Diploma of Translating and Interpreting** (Distinction Average)

Macquarie University (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2014 – Jul 2015

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

# **LANGUAGES**

• English (IELTS-Academic 8.0), Mandarin (Native) and Taiwanese Hokkien (Native).

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- NAATI Accredited Professional Interpreter (Mandarin and English)
- NAATI Accredited Professional Translator (from English to Chinese)

#### REFEREES

Available upon request.